<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-12-25T17:20:39-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning a Programming Language in One Night</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/learning-programming-language-one-night.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/learning-programming-language-one-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/learning-programming-one-night.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Learning a Programming Language in One Night&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a new programming language in one night once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it didn’t really work out at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at my second hackathon, and we were working to build an Android phone app that would integrate with a coffeemaker. We were going to modify the coffeemaker to turn on through bluetooth from the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had split our team into two, so that one team was working on the coffeemaker, and the other team was working on the Android app. My friend and I were both the ones working on the Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem was that none of us had any experience building Android apps, or even programming in Java to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what we did was we decided to learn how to program in Java in a few hours, and then start working on the app. We turned to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com&quot;&gt;Codecademy’s&lt;/a&gt; Java course, and started ripping through the lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we both had no Java or Android app building experience prior to the hackathon, we both did have a decent programming background in Python, and to a smaller extent C++. My friend was in mechanical engineering, and I was in astrophysics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, we were able to go through the lessons very fast. We both completed the all the lessons in under 2 hours, and started working on the Android app. What we needed to do was get the phone to communicate with the coffeemaker using bluetooth through an Arduino microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked up all the API’s needed, and we started looking through tutorials, throwing together code to get the app to work. Even though we had just learned Java, it wasn’t too bad, because the general features of programming languages are pretty similar. I found Java to be a mix between Python and C++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to get the app working and communicating with the Arduino in some small capacity, but unfortunately the other team was not able modify the coffeemaker to do what we wanted it to do, due to a problem with the electric motors we were using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nothing comes easy, or for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So did my friend and I learned a new programming language in just 2 hours? Despite getting an Android app up and running, I’d say we didn’t actually learn how to program in Java. We just learned enough Java to recognize certain patterns that we could hack together in order to make a simple Android app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days after the hackathon, I decided to go back and look at the code that we wrote (or rather, hacked together from a dozen different tutorials), and I found I could not recognize or remember a single bit of Java. I completely forgot everything that I had learned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So moral of the story is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing comes easy, or for free.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to have to work hard to increase your knowledge in something, and one night is not enough to learn something as vast and complex as an entire programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind though that I was by no means a professional developer — I still don’t consider my self one. I was simply a student at that time learning how to program. I’d image someone with more experience could pull it off, but I certainly was not able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/learning-a-programming-language-in-one-night-b67105e2a708&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Don’t Just Set Goals. Achieve Results.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/dont-set-goals-achieve-results.html"/>
   <updated>2017-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/dont-set-goals-achieve-results</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/dont-set-goals-achieve-results.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Don't Just Set Goals. Achieve Results.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is familiar with settings goals, but not everything is familiar with achieving results. It is easy to set goals, but more difficult to achieve them. The good thing is that the more goals you achieve, the more motivated you become, as you see your achievements pile up. The trick is to set reasonable goals so that you are able to achieve them, yet still push yourself each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are seven steps that you may follow to achieve results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create a vision — ask yourself what you want to accomplish, and make this as clear and vibrant in your mind as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Divide and conquer — quantify what you would like to achieve, and break it down into smaller steps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Process into actions — what are the next steps to accomplishing something?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make your commitment public — hold yourself accountable, and set a date that you will accomplish your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Establish accountability — find a mentor or coach to receive regular guidance and follow-up from.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate your successes — record and share your successes, and whenever you feel like giving up, ask yourself why you started in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review your progress — recalibrate and redo the previous steps if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These steps are not things that you do once and forget about. They are long-term steps that help you not only set goals, but to achieve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynda.com/Business-Skills-tutorials/Achieving-Your-Goals/96757-2.html&quot;&gt;Achieving Your Goals by Dave Crenshaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/dont-just-set-goals-achieve-results-aa36985161bd&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Five Pillars of Getting Things Done</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/the-five-pillars-of-getting-things-done.html"/>
   <updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/the-five-pillars-of-getting-things-done</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/getting-things-done.png&quot; alt=&quot;Getting Things Done&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;Getting things done&lt;/a&gt; is not about using the right app or buying the right notebook. It’s a philosophy for living your life in a clear and focused manner, that is agnostic to the underlying system that you choose to implement. In other words, it’s not about the app that you use, or the notebook that you buy. It’s about the mindset that you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five pillars for getting things done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reflect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capture&quot;&gt;Capture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything that is on your mind, that has your attention, or is nagging you, you want to get it out of your head and write it down somewhere. These are things that you need to do, finish, or make decisions on. They are called open loops, and until they are written down somewhere they will remain in your mind, occupying unwanted space. You want your mind to be empty of open loops, in order to make room for more important things, such as ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clarify&quot;&gt;Clarify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Process the stuff that you wrote down. Look at each item that you wrote, and ask yourself: is this something that is actionable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If no, then either delete it, put it on hold until a later date, or put it away for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If yes, then what is the next action? Break it down into the most fundamental action to move things forward. If there is more than one action required, then it is considered a project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an important decision to make.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this stage, also consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are not the appropriate person to do this task, then delegate it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the action takes less than two minutes to do, and you are able to do it at that moment, then do it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Otherwise, defer this action until a later date, and move to the next stage of organizing your tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organize&quot;&gt;Organize&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put your tasks where they belong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tasks that need to be reassessed at a later date can be put in a category called “incubate”. You can set reminders for yourself in a calendar to review these tasks when the time is right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tasks that belong in “reference” can be stored anyway that you like, as long as you keep it simple and maintain it regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everything else can be grouped into a “next actions” category of tasks that need to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next actions can be further organized into more categories, depending on what you find to be useful. Organizing by context can be useful, such as having a “waiting for” and a “projects” list. The important part is to remind yourself of what tasks need to be completed, and to orientate yourself accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try putting everything in one place, and then sort it into lists based on your own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflect&quot;&gt;Reflect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that everything is out of your head. It is important to regularly reflect so that you can trust your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a daily review, preferably at night before you go to sleep, or in the morning when you wake up. Review your calendar to get a map of what is going on in the present and in the future. Look at your lists, review incomplete tasks, and determine if you have any time to complete any tasks, based on how your calendar looks. Stay present with what you are doing, and avoid any anxiety that may come from thinking that you may have missed something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a weekly review. Take a few steps back, and get a larger picture of the tasks that are going on that are incomplete. Look at your “projects” list and calendar, and stay focused on the long-term scope of what you want to do. This is also a great time to start planning ahead, and you will actually have room in your head for creative ideas on what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engage&quot;&gt;Engage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to be present with what you are doing, and this is based on how engaged you are with everything else that is going on in your life. If you properly apply the other four pillars of getting things done, then you can trust that what you are doing in the present time is the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, getting things done is all about being present with what you are doing, and being able to have the space in your mind to do the things that you need to do. It’s okay to fall off the wagon every once in a while — if you’re not, then you’re playing a big enough game. The important thing is to know how to get back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;Getting things done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/the-five-pillars-of-getting-things-done-9fdb2a3aff0e&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Just Did It.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/just-did-it.html"/>
   <updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/just-did-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/just-did-it.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Just did it.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common roadblock that many people — including myself — come across when trying to do anything, is always waiting for things to be perfect before starting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a trap.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are never perfect, and if you always wait, you will never get anything done, or do what you want to do.
The solution to this problem? &lt;strong&gt;Just do it.&lt;/strong&gt; No matter how bad or unfinished something is, aim to get it 80% of the way there, and then ship it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind of like what I just did just now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/just-did-it-fe0ae59d4379&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
