<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2018-09-23T23:10:16-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Focus Focus</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/focus-focus.html"/>
   <updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/focus-focus</id>
   <content type="html">
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>One Step at a Time.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/one-step-at-a-time.html"/>
   <updated>2018-09-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/one-step-at-a-time</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Often, when people first start out trying to achieve a goal, they try to set ambitious goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/one-step-at-a-time.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, there is nothing wrong with that. In fact, you should be setting ambitious goals, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, they set ambitious goals, and then they have unrealistic expectations as to how it will all turn out. When they eventually fail, they get discouraged, and then in many cases never try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more reasonable approach is to instead start small. Have big, ambitious, extraordinary goals, but break them down into many smaller ones. How small? So small that it’s almost impossible for you to not achieve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s say you want to lose weight. Rather than telling yourself that you will suddenly go from sitting in front of a computer all day, to going to the gym every single day at 6:00 am for 2 hours, set a goal of just simply walking more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to quantify it if you can. Invest in a cheap pedometer, and see how many steps you usually take, and make a reasonable goal (say, 50 more steps). Then, stick to it. Build the habit. Enjoy those small wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you start building the habit, and associating achieving your goal with a good feeling, you will want to do it more and more. Hopefully, by then it’ll start to feel weird if you don’t achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, you start to build up the habit even more, and set more and more ambitious goals. Before you know it, you’ll be running marathons. And losing weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start small, and build your way up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/one-step-at-a-time-83b1d0a1cc87&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Wait?</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/why-wait.html"/>
   <updated>2018-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/why-wait</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every new year, people make resolutions to be better. For whatever reason, New Years Eve is special: a new year, means a new you, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/why-wait.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you think about it, New Years Eve isn’t all that special of an event. What makes the passing of a year different from say, the passing of a month? Or the passing of a day? Why don’t people celebrate other points on the calendar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new year shouldn’t be the only time when you decide to be better, and you shouldn’t have to wait for the new year in order to set goals for yourself. A new year is no different from a new month, or a new day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any moment of your life is a good time for you to start improving yourself. Don’t wait for next year, start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/why-wait-6e43345a1234&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Avoiding the Perfection Trap</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/avoiding-the-perfection-trap.html"/>
   <updated>2018-09-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/avoiding-the-perfection-trap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A common roadblock that many people come across when starting something new is the idea that they must wait for perfect conditions to happen in order for them to start. This idea ends up being a trap, as perfect conditions rarely ever occur — most people end up never starting whatever it is that they wanted to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trap can be seen whenever someone procrastinates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/avoiding-the perfection-trap.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, the reason for procrastination is the preconceived notion that whatever it is they must be doing must be done to perfection. As a result, they avoid doing it, until a moment of insight comes and everything suddenly falls into place. Ultimately, the reason why people never end up doing whatever it is that they want to do in life is because of procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can best avoid this trap by just starting whatever it is that you must start, no matter how bad it will end up being. It is better to do something that isn’t completely perfect, than to not have anything to show. In reality, things in life are rarely perfect anyways, and those who at least have something to show end up successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/avoiding-the-perfection-trap-64de769aa602&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Importance of Doing</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/the-importance-of-doing.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-importance-of-doing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is an interesting lesson hidden within &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Little_Prince&quot;&gt;Le Petit Prince&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antoine_de_Saint-Exup%C3%A9ry&quot;&gt;Antoine de Saint-Exupéry&lt;/a&gt; (one of my favourite children’s book of all time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/the-importance-of-doing.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The Little Prince&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the story, the Little Prince visits a planet inhabited solely by a geographer. The geographer gets excited, thinking that the Little Prince is an explorer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Oh, look! Here is an explorer!” he exclaimed to himself when he saw the little prince coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The little prince sat down on the table and panted a little. He had already traveled so much and so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Where do you come from?” the old gentleman said to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What is that big book?” said the little prince. “What are you doing?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I am a geographer,” the old gentleman said to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What is a geographer?” asked the little prince.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A geographer is a scholar who knows the location of all the seas, rivers, towns, mountains, and deserts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds great! The Little Prince has finally found someone who seemed to know a thing or two about something, unlike the previous people he had visited. Upon further inquiry though, the Little Prince discovers something about the geographer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/the-importance-of-doing-geographer.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The Geographer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Your planet is very beautiful,” he said. “Has it any oceans?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I couldn’t tell you,” said the geographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Ah!” The little prince was disappointed. “Has it any mountains?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I couldn’t tell you,” said the geographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“And towns, and rivers, and deserts?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I couldn’t tell you that, either.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But you are a geographer!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Exactly,” the geographer said. “But I am not an explorer. I haven’t a single explorer on my planet. It is not the geographer who goes out to count the towns, the rivers, the mountains, the seas, the oceans, and the deserts. The geographer is much too important to go loafing about. He does not leave his desk. But he receives the explorers in his study. He asks them questions, and he notes down what they recall of their travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, someone who spends too much time reading is like the geographer: ignorant of what is truly going on in the world around them, and lacking the experience that comes from actually exploring, and doing what one reads about in books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Little_Prince&quot;&gt;The Little Prince by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/the-importance-of-doing-bf450ba8884f&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How I Stop Worrying (And Start Living)</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-stop-worrying.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-stop-worrying</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/how-to-stop-worrying.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is something that I learned from reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Stop_Worrying_and_Start_Living&quot;&gt;“How to Stop Worrying and Start Living”, by Dale Carnegie&lt;/a&gt;, which has helped me immensely in overcoming moments in my life where I have experienced a lot of worry and anxiety:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarify exactly what is it that is bothering you, and what is causing you to feel the way you do.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, let’s say you are worried about being judged because you got a weird haircut. Your weird haircut is bothering you because you are afraid that everyone will make fun of you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now take this scenario, and imagine the worse possible situation that may arise out of it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you got a weird haircut and are worried about being made fun of, then the worse possible situation is everyone you know making fun of your for your haircut, and you being shunned from society.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The next step is to accept as best you can the worst possible situation.&lt;/strong&gt; People are going to make fun of you? Let them, it’s no big deal. If that is what is going to happen, then it will happen, and there is nothing much you can do if that happens but to wait it out. If you get shunned from society, prepare to move to a new country.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The final step is to meditate, and then start coming up with solutions to mitigate the worst possible scenario.&lt;/strong&gt; Now that you have accepted the worst possible scenario, you have nowhere to go but up. Start coming up with solutions to make the situation better. If you got a weird haircut, maybe you can still style it differently to make it look better. Or you can just wear a hat until it grows back. It’s hair after all.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow through with your plan and prepare for the worst.&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully by now, you’ll have realized how silly your worries were to begin with — except now you have clear head, and are able to rationally handle the situation. Follow whatever solutions you came up with, and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, before I get to the final step, I realize how silly my worries were to begin with. Often, without clarifying what it was that was bothering me, my mind ends up running wild with irrational fears and anxieties that had nothing to do with my original worry. I find that meditation helps immensely to put things into perspective, and to be able to think rationally about a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a favourite quote of mine that sums it all up nicely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve had a lot of worries in my life, most of which never happened. -Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Stop_Worrying_and_Start_Living&quot;&gt;How to Stop Worrying and Start Living by Dale Carnegie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/how-i-stop-worrying-and-start-living-3ab8107616a0&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Building Resilience</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/building-resilience.html"/>
   <updated>2018-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/building-resilience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Facing new challenges, and bouncing back from uncomfortable, difficult situations requires a high threshold for resilience. Building resilience is a habit and skill that takes time to develop. When you are in a stressful situation, it can be very emotionally draining, but when you overcome it, you become stronger. Always strive to reflect and learn from your experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Avoidance of small mistakes makes big ones more severe — Nassim Taleb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/building-resilience.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five activities that you can participate in, that will help you raise your resilience threshold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice asking for things, and face rejection.&lt;/strong&gt; Try asking for things that you are not sure you will receive. It doesn’t cost anything to ask. When you get rejected, don’t focus on the negative thoughts, but praise yourself for asking in the first place. Stay positive, and never apologize for asking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn something new.&lt;/strong&gt; Put yourself outside of your comfort zone, and have humbling experiences, where you feel incompetent and uncomfortable. Doing this creates opportunities to fail and go back and try again, building resilience. Learn how to fail ad bounce back.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face uncomfortable situation.&lt;/strong&gt; We all naturally gravitate towards routine, and to things that are familiar to us, that play to our strengths. Similar to above, putting yourself in uncomfortable, unfamiliar and challenging situations will build your resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage your energy.&lt;/strong&gt; Take care of your body, and ensure you are eating healthy and getting enough sleep. Be aware of how your energy and productivity fluctuates throughout the day, and plan your day accordingly. Plan ahead for times that you know will be difficult, and prepare yourself to deal with it. Make sure to always find time to rest and recover from challenging situations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice positive thinking.&lt;/strong&gt; Negative events are only temporary, and in many cases you can change the situation. Pay attention to how you respond to negative situations or criticism, and what your internal dialogue is like. Finally, make sure to keep the situation in perspective, and do not blow things out of proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve failed over and over again in my life, and that is why I succeed — Michael Jordan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection is one of the most valuable and most under-used processes of learning. It is important to take the time to go back and learn from difficult experiences, in order to build a resilience threshold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluate your actions.&lt;/strong&gt; What could you have done differently? How did you handle the situation? Did you stay positive?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose your attitude.&lt;/strong&gt; The first option is to be completely negative. The second option is to be completely positive, but unrealistic. The third and best option is to be positive, yet constructive. You can acknowledge any negative attitude that you may have, but do not let it define you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect with an advisory board.&lt;/strong&gt; Have people you trust to confide in, to ask for feedback on your performance, and to ask for constructive, action-orientated advice on how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximize your recovery.&lt;/strong&gt; Take a break, both physically and emotionally. Step away from the situation and do something else for a period of time. After you have recovered, and have more energy, reconnect with a fresh perspective on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let it go.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes, despite your effort, it is best to just let things go and move on to something else.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Where there is no struggle, there is no strength — Oprah Winfrey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building resilience is not something that you learn from reading a book. It is something that needs to be practiced daily, in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynda.com/Leadership-Management-tutorials/Building-Resilience/170777-2.html&quot;&gt;Building Resilience by Tatiana Kolovou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/building-resilience-8a1e058d2294&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quality or Quantity?</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/quality-or-quantity.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/quality-or-quantity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An old adage that many people often hear is “quality over quantity”. Given a scenario where one must choose between something of high quality, or something of high quantity, one should choose high quality. In many cases, this is true. But does this apply everywhere in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.ca/Art-Fear-Observations-Rewards-Artmaking/dp/0961454733&quot;&gt;Art &amp;amp; Fear: Observations on the Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking&lt;/a&gt;, by David Bayles, he tells of a parable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The ceramics teacher announced on opening day that he was dividing the class into two groups. All those on the left side of the studio, he said, would be graded solely on the quantity of work they produced, all those on the right solely on its quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His procedure was simple: on the final day of class he would bring in his bathroom scales and weigh the work of the “quantity” group: fifty pound of pots rated an “A”, forty pounds a “B”, and so on. Those being graded on “quality”, however, needed to produce only one pot, albeit a “perfect” one, to get an “A”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you guess which group did the best? Can you see which group you would best identify with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are, it is the group on the right: those being judged on the quality of their single pot. Surely, the group on the left — those being judged for quantity — will not have as high a standard as the group on the right, and simply just produce mediocre work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/quality-or-quantity.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our lives, we tend to act like the group on the right. We always aim to produce things that are of high quality, that are perfect — often on the first try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in doing so, we also end up &lt;a href=&quot;https://hungryminds.quora.com/Avoiding-The-Perfection-Trap&quot;&gt;stuck in a perfection trap&lt;/a&gt;, in analysis paralysis. We spend too much time planning and waiting for perfect conditions, as opposed to actually doing whatever it is that we set out to do. In many cases, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hungryminds.quora.com/Perfect-is-the-Enemy-of-Good&quot;&gt;perfect is the enemy of good&lt;/a&gt;, and we never get around to any doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is fine though, because in the end when we do complete what we set out to do, our work will always be of higher quality than if we had just done it without all that careful planning. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not always the case. A distinction should be made between the final product, and the rough drafts. The final product is what we present to the world, while the rough drafts are what we make when we are creating the final products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Design_of_Everyday_Things&quot;&gt;The Design of Everyday Things&lt;/a&gt;, by Don Norman, he talks about a concept called Human-centered design (HCD). He goes on to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The HCD principle is to avoid specifying the problem as long as possible but instead to iterate upon repeated approximations. This is done through rapid tests of ideas, and after each test modifying the approach and the problem definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design, and indeed many ventures in our lives are best done in an iterative process, where, although each step in the iteration process may not be perfect or of high quality, the sheer number of steps taken, whereby the work is incrementally improved upon, results in work of high quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, one should always strive for quality and perfection, but understand that to get there, one has to pay their dues so to speak, and go through the drudgery of repetition after repetition, improving one’s work in tiny increments before perfection or high quality can be achieved. The caveat here is that mistakes must be learned from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now you probably have guessed how the parable ends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Well, came grading time and a curious fact emerged: the works of highest quality were all produced by the group being graded for quantity. It seems that while the “quantity” group was busily churning out piles of work”and learning from their mistakes”the “quality” group had sat theorizing about perfection, and in the end had little more to show for their efforts than grandiose theories and a pile of dead clay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson to be learned here is that quality rarely ever arises out of nothing. To achieve perfection and quality, one must first have to go through an iterative process of constantly testing and refining one’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practice makes perfect, and quantity leads to quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/quality-or-quantity-d1a264d39de&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning a Programming Language in One Night</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/learning-programming-language-one-night.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/learning-programming-language-one-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/learning-programming-one-night.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a new programming language in one night once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it didn’t really work out at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at my second hackathon, and we were working to build an Android phone app that would integrate with a coffeemaker. We were going to modify the coffeemaker to turn on through bluetooth from the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had split our team into two, so that one team was working on the coffeemaker, and the other team was working on the Android app. My friend and I were both the ones working on the Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem was that none of us had any experience building Android apps, or even programming in Java to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what we did was we decided to learn how to program in Java in a few hours, and then start working on the app. We turned to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com&quot;&gt;Codecademy’s&lt;/a&gt; Java course, and started ripping through the lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we both had no Java or Android app building experience prior to the hackathon, we both did have a decent programming background in Python, and to a smaller extent C++. My friend was in mechanical engineering, and I was in astrophysics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, we were able to go through the lessons very fast. We both completed the all the lessons in under 2 hours, and started working on the Android app. What we needed to do was get the phone to communicate with the coffeemaker using bluetooth through an Arduino microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked up all the API’s needed, and we started looking through tutorials, throwing together code to get the app to work. Even though we had just learned Java, it wasn’t too bad, because the general features of programming languages are pretty similar. I found Java to be a mix between Python and C++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to get the app working and communicating with the Arduino in some small capacity, but unfortunately the other team was not able modify the coffeemaker to do what we wanted it to do, due to a problem with the electric motors we were using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nothing comes easy, or for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So did my friend and I learned a new programming language in just 2 hours? Despite getting an Android app up and running, I’d say we didn’t actually learn how to program in Java. We just learned enough Java to recognize certain patterns that we could hack together in order to make a simple Android app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days after the hackathon, I decided to go back and look at the code that we wrote (or rather, hacked together from a dozen different tutorials), and I found I could not recognize or remember a single bit of Java. I completely forgot everything that I had learned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So moral of the story is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing comes easy, or for free.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to have to work hard to increase your knowledge in something, and one night is not enough to learn something as vast and complex as an entire programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind though that I was by no means a professional developer — I still don’t consider my self one. I was simply a student at that time learning how to program. I’d image someone with more experience could pull it off, but I certainly was not able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/learning-a-programming-language-in-one-night-b67105e2a708&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Don’t Just Set Goals. Achieve Results.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/dont-set-goals-achieve-results.html"/>
   <updated>2017-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/dont-set-goals-achieve-results</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/dont-set-goals-achieve-results.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is familiar with settings goals, but not everything is familiar with achieving results. It is easy to set goals, but more difficult to achieve them. The good thing is that the more goals you achieve, the more motivated you become, as you see your achievements pile up. The trick is to set reasonable goals so that you are able to achieve them, yet still push yourself each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are seven steps that you may follow to achieve results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create a vision — ask yourself what you want to accomplish, and make this as clear and vibrant in your mind as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Divide and conquer — quantify what you would like to achieve, and break it down into smaller steps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Process into actions — what are the next steps to accomplishing something?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make your commitment public — hold yourself accountable, and set a date that you will accomplish your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Establish accountability — find a mentor or coach to receive regular guidance and follow-up from.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate your successes — record and share your successes, and whenever you feel like giving up, ask yourself why you started in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review your progress — recalibrate and redo the previous steps if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These steps are not things that you do once and forget about. They are long-term steps that help you not only set goals, but to achieve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynda.com/Business-Skills-tutorials/Achieving-Your-Goals/96757-2.html&quot;&gt;Achieving Your Goals by Dave Crenshaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/dont-just-set-goals-achieve-results-aa36985161bd&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Five Pillars of Getting Things Done</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/the-five-pillars-of-getting-things-done.html"/>
   <updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-five-pillars-of-getting-things-done</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/getting-things-done.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wikipedia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;Getting things done&lt;/a&gt; is not about using the right app or buying the right notebook. It’s a philosophy for living your life in a clear and focused manner, that is agnostic to the underlying system that you choose to implement. In other words, it’s not about the app that you use, or the notebook that you buy. It’s about the mindset that you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five pillars for getting things done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reflect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capture&quot;&gt;Capture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything that is on your mind, that has your attention, or is nagging you, you want to get it out of your head and write it down somewhere. These are things that you need to do, finish, or make decisions on. They are called open loops, and until they are written down somewhere they will remain in your mind, occupying unwanted space. You want your mind to be empty of open loops, in order to make room for more important things, such as ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clarify&quot;&gt;Clarify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Process the stuff that you wrote down. Look at each item that you wrote, and ask yourself: is this something that is actionable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If no, then either delete it, put it on hold until a later date, or put it away for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If yes, then what is the next action? Break it down into the most fundamental action to move things forward. If there is more than one action required, then it is considered a project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an important decision to make.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this stage, also consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are not the appropriate person to do this task, then delegate it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the action takes less than two minutes to do, and you are able to do it at that moment, then do it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Otherwise, defer this action until a later date, and move to the next stage of organizing your tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organize&quot;&gt;Organize&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put your tasks where they belong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tasks that need to be reassessed at a later date can be put in a category called “incubate”. You can set reminders for yourself in a calendar to review these tasks when the time is right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tasks that belong in “reference” can be stored anyway that you like, as long as you keep it simple and maintain it regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everything else can be grouped into a “next actions” category of tasks that need to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next actions can be further organized into more categories, depending on what you find to be useful. Organizing by context can be useful, such as having a “waiting for” and a “projects” list. The important part is to remind yourself of what tasks need to be completed, and to orientate yourself accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try putting everything in one place, and then sort it into lists based on your own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflect&quot;&gt;Reflect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that everything is out of your head. It is important to regularly reflect so that you can trust your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a daily review, preferably at night before you go to sleep, or in the morning when you wake up. Review your calendar to get a map of what is going on in the present and in the future. Look at your lists, review incomplete tasks, and determine if you have any time to complete any tasks, based on how your calendar looks. Stay present with what you are doing, and avoid any anxiety that may come from thinking that you may have missed something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a weekly review. Take a few steps back, and get a larger picture of the tasks that are going on that are incomplete. Look at your “projects” list and calendar, and stay focused on the long-term scope of what you want to do. This is also a great time to start planning ahead, and you will actually have room in your head for creative ideas on what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engage&quot;&gt;Engage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to be present with what you are doing, and this is based on how engaged you are with everything else that is going on in your life. If you properly apply the other four pillars of getting things done, then you can trust that what you are doing in the present time is the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, getting things done is all about being present with what you are doing, and being able to have the space in your mind to do the things that you need to do. It’s okay to fall off the wagon every once in a while — if you’re not, then you’re playing a big enough game. The important thing is to know how to get back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;Getting things done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/the-five-pillars-of-getting-things-done-9fdb2a3aff0e&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Just Did It.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/just-did-it.html"/>
   <updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/just-did-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/just-did-it.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Death to Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common roadblock that many people — including myself — come across when trying to do anything, is always waiting for things to be perfect before starting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a trap.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are never perfect, and if you always wait, you will never get anything done, or do what you want to do.
The solution to this problem? &lt;strong&gt;Just do it.&lt;/strong&gt; No matter how bad or unfinished something is, aim to get it 80% of the way there, and then ship it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind of like what I just did just now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@LeNPaul/just-did-it-fe0ae59d4379&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
